# Anupam Patra

anupam-coder.github.io/MyPortfolio/ anupampatrabbsr1995@gmail.com | +91-8984127934

# **SUMMARY**

I am a web developer with 5+ years of experience having expertise in frontend and exposure to backend. I can design and develop web apps using the latest technologies to deliver the product with quality code. I am very good at UI fundamentals and technologies and can adapt to most of the frontend frameworks quickly.

# LINKS

Github:// anupam-coder LinkedIn:// anupam-patra-921634ab LeetCode:// anupampatrabbsr1995

# **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Profecient with:

HTML • CSS • Javascript • ReactJS

Redux • Jest/Enzyme •

Familiar with:
Java • Angular 7 • NodeJS • AWS •
Cypress • UI-Automation • Data
Structures • Algorithms

#### **TOOLS**

JIRA • Confluence • Postman • Swagger

Microsoft Dynamics CRM • Splunk

# CERTIFICATIONS

Certifications in Java, Css, Javascript from Hackerrank Certified React developer from Udemy Certified NodeJS developer from Udemy

# **EDUCATION**

#### **VSSUT.BURLA**

B.Tech in Electronics and Telecommunication

May 2017 Veer Surendra Sai University of Technology,Burla

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **OPENTEXT** | Senior Software Engineer

June 2023 - Present | Hyderabad, Telangana

- Implemented logic for release number and version number, enabling user to create releases for thier items properly and point the latest release/version.
- Utilized: ReactJS, Marionette, Backbone

#### **ACCENTURE** | APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT SENIOR ANALYST

Sept 2021 - June 2023 | Bengaluru, Karnataka

(CLIENT: UK GOVT (MHRA))

- Created UI for UK Gov from scratch did all the setup for onboarding an user and healthcare organisation.
- Utilized: ReactJS, Redux, Typescript

(CLIENT: GOLDMAN SACHS)

- Developed a Fraud/Exception review page for agents to verify the transaction and send a decision. This helped the client to identify forgery/illegal activities.
- <u>Utilized:</u> ReactJS, Redux, Jest/enzyme, Java, Gitlab, Automation

#### WIPRO | ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT

March 2019 - Sept 2021 | Bengaluru, Karnataka

(CLIENT: ALLIANZ)

- Helped expanding business in ASEAN countries by creating new landing pages with specific features like language change, activation code generate modal for respective partners.
- Increased team's unit testing coverage using Cypress and Jest.
- Utilized: ReactJS, Styled components, Jira, Cypress, Jest, Github

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

### COLOR GAME: github.io/ColorGame

- RGB code of an unknown colour will be given for e.g- RGB (255, 0, 0). Guess the right colour out of random colours by clicking on them.
- <u>Utilized:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### TYPE LIKE FLASH: github.io/TypeLikeFlash

- This is a speed test of our typing speed. The result is delivered in words per minute.
- Utilized: HTML,CSS,JavaScript, ReactJS

## THE NAME SEARCH PORTAL: github.io/NameSearch

- The app basically works for users to generate name suggestions for any entered keywords.
- <u>Utilized:</u> HTML,CSS,JavaScript, ReactJS